[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee9", "question": "Which royal house consisted of Henry IV, Henry V and Henry VI?", "answer": "House of Lancaster", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b63f", "question": "What spice comes from the herb called cilantro?", "answer": "Coriander", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e4", "question": "What hangs from the roof of a limestone cave?", "answer": "Stalactites", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b932", "question": "What law school did Bill and Hillary Clinton attend?", "answer": "Yale", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cab", "question": "What fictional polo player was first played on screen by swimmer Buster Crabbe?", "answer": "Flash Gordon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c875", "question": "What type of animal are flying foxes?", "answer": "Bats", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c5a", "question": "Which fictional singer was Kevin Costner hired to guard in the 1992 movie \"The Bodyguard\"?", "answer": "Rachel Marron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029f1ccad1ec93f27df75b", "question": "At what popular Seattle market did Starbucks open its first store in 1971?", "answer": "Pike Place", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfde", "question": "How many tournaments make up a Grand Slam in golf?", "answer": "4\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe768b2eec85e375820b2a5", "question": "What does the orange color on Ireland's flag represent?", "answer": "Protestants", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cba", "question": "What is the third letter of the Greek alphabet?", "answer": "Gamma", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339140", "question": "Which opera was the last composed by Benjamin Britten?", "answer": "Death in Venice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc8816de0eb824d4052fc", "question": "What is Camp David's official name?", "answer": "Naval Support Facility Thurmont -- President Eisenhower named it Camp David after his grandson, David.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d4", "question": "What does the abbreviation VH1 stand for in the TV station by the same name?", "answer": "Video Hits 1", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc6", "question": "Who rode Rocinante?", "answer": "Don Quixote", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601736eb44491cbd7c5a1782", "question": "What is the blood-sucking creature of Puerto Rican lore?", "answer": "El Chupacabra -- When small animals get mysteriously attacked in Puerto Rico, this animal-vampire figure is said to be to blame.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fb1bffff497e33de805791b", "question": "What can be found inside a baseball?", "answer": "Rubber or cork, and yarn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e87", "question": "What future celebrity made an appearance as Opie in \"Andy Griffith\"?", "answer": "Ron Howard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339245", "question": "What is the birth country of Russell Crowe?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7c", "question": "What beer\u2019s name means \u201clion\u2019s brew\u201d in German?", "answer": "Lowenbrau", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7ca3f877e98cb97778a04", "question": "What Cape will you find at the tip of Africa?", "answer": "Cape of Good Hope", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a75f", "question": "How many countries border Chile?", "answer": "3", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b517", "question": "What is the only alcoholic drink one can buy in the dry Moore county in Tennessee?", "answer": "Jack Daniel's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c6", "question": "What year was Bram Stoker's novel \"Dracula\" published?", "answer": "1897", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a46c", "question": "Tarifa is the southern most point on the mainland of which country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133933b", "question": "On the TV show \"South Park\", which character wears a blue hat with a red pom-pom on it?", "answer": "Stan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c75d0775fa611bce67d8", "question": "What is the name of the University of Georgia's mascot?", "answer": "The Georgia Bulldogs have a bulldog as their mascot and his name is \"Uga\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffe502447818f5674af01b8", "question": "\"Les Fauves\" was a name given to a group of artists that also included Matisse. What is its literal meaning of \"Les Fauves\"?", "answer": "The Wild Beasts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c57b", "question": "What is the common name for \"alopecia\"?", "answer": "Baldness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3dd", "question": "Who did Arthur Bremer try to assassinate in 1972?", "answer": "George Wallace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600398b657a0e35c43f8389d", "question": "James McNeill Whistler's Arrangement in Grey and Black No.1 is better known by what other name?", "answer": "Whistler's Mother\u00a0-- It is exhibited in the Mus\u00e9e d'Orsay in Paris, having been bought by the French state in 1891.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b47501dd7bf43be5e7c0", "question": "What ingredient makes up at least 51% of bourbon mash?", "answer": "Corn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febbcbf7e83c707845b2150", "question": "What is the name of the NFL's all-star exhibition game?", "answer": "Pro Bowl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feba95a7e83c707845b20d5", "question": "Which astronomical celestial event generally occurs on the same date as the International Day of Happiness?", "answer": "March Equinox", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eaf", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"Witness for the Prosecution\"?", "answer": "Tyrone Power", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d118174fea7fe947a22281", "question": "What metal has the chemical symbol Pb?", "answer": "Lead", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd69ffe6c0f9723ab15cb31", "question": "Which British monarch is responsible for transforming Buckingham House into a palace?", "answer": "George IV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d0", "question": "By area, what is the smallest of the Great Lakes?", "answer": "Lake Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b916", "question": "What 2 letters in scrabble have the highest point value?", "answer": "Q and Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339552", "question": "What TV show centered on the exploits of physicist Dr. Sam Beckett?", "answer": "Quantum Leap", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a3b", "question": "The Stephen Sondheim Broadway musical \"Sunday in the Park with George\" was based on a painting by what artist?", "answer": "Georges Seurat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20d", "question": "Which country were the 1920 Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a1", "question": "Clams and snails are part of what phylum or biological classification?", "answer": "Mollusks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59067e7aff9c0647b50a807b", "question": "Who was awarded the 2016 Nobel Prize for Literature?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be8d", "question": "What measurement was derived from the rope to which a boat's \"chip log\" was tied?", "answer": "The knot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b25f", "question": "In 1966, Johnny Cash briefly shared a Nashville apartment with what other country legend?", "answer": "Waylon Jennings", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59db77bc0ab2c8f322317fee", "question": "Which holiday did Canada Day replace in 1982?", "answer": "Dominion Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c079", "question": "What is the fear of knees known as?", "answer": "Genuphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febbafc7e83c707845b2148", "question": "Who played the lead in \"The Last Boy Scout\"?", "answer": "Bruce Willis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c11", "question": "In what year was comedian Stephen Colbert born?", "answer": "1964", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd4", "question": "Who killed Count Dooku by cutting off his head?", "answer": "Anakin Skywalker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a6", "question": "In what city do The Simpsons live?", "answer": "Springfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6a1", "question": "What US road sign is typically shaped like a triangle?", "answer": "Yield", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988c", "question": "What Canadian television series did hip hop star Drake star as a main character?", "answer": "Degrassi: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e3f35d5cb9e8bda6821363", "question": "What ancient city did Swiss explorer Johann Ludwig Burckhardt introduce to the Western world in 1812?", "answer": "Petra", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb1", "question": "Which ingredient provides the red color in a Tequila Sunrise?", "answer": "Grenadine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a48", "question": "In the TV series, which one of the four main characters on \"Sex and the City\" had a baby?", "answer": "Miranda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febda007e83c707845b2180", "question": "In 2009, which artist set the record for the longest leap to number-one in Billboard Hot 100 history?", "answer": "Kelly Clarkson's 2009 hit \"My Life Would Suck Without You\" jumped from number-97 to number-1 in the course of a week.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c3", "question": "Who wrote and performed the theme song for the movie \"Philadelphia\"?", "answer": "Bruce Springsteen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acdf", "question": "Who invented the radio alarm clock?", "answer": "James F. Reynolds", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b788", "question": "What style of pants is named after an island in the Gulf of Naples?", "answer": "Capri pants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3ecf58b5801b8f54a7faf", "question": "Peleus and Thetis were the parents of what famed warrior?", "answer": "Achilles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c27f", "question": "What is the oldest and most numerous class of animals?", "answer": "Insects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594d08381a1c922dd1ac64c1", "question": "Nordic and Alpine are two main genres of which sport?", "answer": "Skiing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ded197ea2747c8aff16d34", "question": "Vodka and coffee liqueur make what cocktail?", "answer": "Black Russian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a336", "question": "Who played Laurie Strode in the 1978 horror film \"Halloween\"?", "answer": "Jamie Lee Curtis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5a3f6ce05a3942286e0b", "question": "\"Life is Beautiful\" has been named one of the top-five favorite films of which prominent figure?", "answer": "Pope John Paul II", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa56cec73aa70ea0b70b2d", "question": "Which two towns were destroyed and buried when Mount Vesuvius erupted in 79 A.D.?", "answer": "Pompeii and Herculaneum were both destroyed by the eruption in 79 A.D.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febb17a7e83c707845b210d", "question": "What are the fuzzy ends of a dandelion called?", "answer": "Seed Heads", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a2", "question": "Who is known as Eminem?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b68", "question": "On what cartoon do the main characters live in the fictional town of Bikini Bottom?", "answer": "SpongeBob SquarePants", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b87", "question": "What bands early album titles had a Spanish flair including \"Tres Hombres\", \"Fandango\", and \"Deguello\"?", "answer": "ZZ Top", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b0", "question": "Who played the role of Andy Dufresne in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Tim Robbins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339482", "question": "Who directed the 1969 movie \"The Wild Bunch\"?", "answer": "Sam Peckinpah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339981", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who does Homer consider to be his best friend?", "answer": "Barney Gumble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa552bc73aa70ea0b70b22", "question": "The Black Forest is located in what European country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba5f", "question": "In what Missouri town did Mark Twain grow up?", "answer": "Hannibal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf41", "question": "Who invented the electrical bass?", "answer": "Leo Fender", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc9", "question": "What can a lycanthrope do ?", "answer": "Change into a wolf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d73", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"Life Among the Lowly\"?", "answer": "Uncle Tom's Cabin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa5fb6ce05a3942286ec8", "question": "Who directed the film \"Home Alone?\"", "answer": "Chris Columbus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be0c", "question": "The word \"grenade\" derives from the name of what fruit?", "answer": "Pomegranate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a9", "question": "Who considered founding a utopian art colony at Arles in France prior to his suicide?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339862", "question": "In Disney's Pinocchio, what colour is the fairy who gives life to Pinocchio?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fbf", "question": "Who wrote the short novel \"The Old Man and the Sea\"?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff519ebff04d658268c9303", "question": "Which nihilist philosopher famously spoke of \"the death of God?\"", "answer": "Friedrich Nietzsche's philosophy predicted the erosion of organized religions and ethical frameworks.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea337dff048f679a45aaee", "question": "What animal name literally means \"pig-fish\"?", "answer": "Porpoise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2d", "question": "What dessert consists of beaten egg whites, sugar, and cream of tartar?", "answer": "Meringue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e5", "question": "What US state depicts Delicate Arch on its license plates?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a67120565ad31a57c7d9", "question": "What is the name of the first nuclear-powered merchant ship?", "answer": "NS Savannah", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c1b", "question": "The comic books and movie titled \"300\" is based off of which famous battle?", "answer": "The Battle of Thermopylae", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c1", "question": "Who was Spenser's sidekick in the TV show \"Spenser: For Hire\"?", "answer": "Hawk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e0", "question": "What fashion designer owns Maxim's restaurant in Paris?", "answer": "Pierre Cardin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ac", "question": "What is the singer Meat Loafs real name?", "answer": "Michael Lee Aday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc22cec223966ae8f8872", "question": "Actor Veronica Cartwright reacting with genuine shock during the \"chest-bursting scene\" of which classic horror movie?", "answer": "\"Alien\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a15d", "question": "The Golden and Silver Lions are awarded at which film festival?", "answer": "Venice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922a", "question": "What Welsh songstress has performed the themes for three different Bond movies?", "answer": "Shirley Bassey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b93", "question": "Who is Becky Thatcher's boyfriend?", "answer": "Tom Sawyer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76b30eec85e375820b2bd", "question": "Where did Oktoberfest originate?", "answer": "Munich, Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339650", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1946 movie \"The Yearling\"?", "answer": "Deer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b2", "question": "What athlete played co-pilot Roger Murdock in the 1980 movie \"Airplane!\"?", "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338890", "question": "What is Bruce Wayne's heroic identity?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a299", "question": "Who directed the 1978 film \"Halloween\"?", "answer": "John Carpenter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a8", "question": "How many years did prohibition last in the US?", "answer": "13", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc34", "question": "Which US state is home to CNN?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c69", "question": "What is the name of Tony Manero's dance partner in the 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "Stephanie Mangano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a162cd9f01ec323f8491733", "question": "Tradionally, what does a Fletcher make?", "answer": "Arrows", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6b27afb6c85e9e634ff3e", "question": "Who was king of England from 1422 until 1461?", "answer": "Henry Vl", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a43f", "question": "Which country is home to the Great Barrier Reef?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133892b", "question": "Thor is the son of which Norse god?", "answer": "Odin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921d", "question": "In which movie does Hugh Grant play a London bookshop owner?", "answer": "Notting Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a52b", "question": "The majority of the Sierra Nevada Mountains are located in which state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4dc", "question": "What fruit comes in Muscat and Scuppernong variety?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a91c", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Point?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecd0ecec223966ae8f88bc", "question": "Who is the flame-shooting guitarist in \"Mad Max: Fury Road\"?", "answer": "Sean Hape", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6c", "question": "Who played the role of TV's J. J. Starbuck?", "answer": "Dale Robertson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a72d", "question": "Dover is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d6e92596a59cbdfbd3af", "question": "What was Henry Ford\u2019s original design for a car called?", "answer": "Quadricycle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f36", "question": "What's the protagonist's name in the 1931 movie \"Little Caesar\"?", "answer": "Rico", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd9699a23c87fd04dd15e0a", "question": "What was the name of Odysseus\u2019 dog?", "answer": "Argos", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a19", "question": "What UK band had a #1 hit in 1981 with the song \"Don\u2019t You Want Me\"?", "answer": "Human League", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba5c5874c93a3298b2153", "question": "\"An Inconvenient Truth\" is a 2006 documentary film directed by Davis Guggenheim about what subject?", "answer": "Global Warming", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d0", "question": "Who won an Oscar for his role in the movie \"Ray\"?", "answer": "Jamie Foxx", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339178", "question": "What picture hangs on Andy Dufresne's cell wall in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "A picture of Albert Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66bb2a5bfecdd737e0887", "question": "What was Merriam-Webster's word of the year for 2019?", "answer": "They", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9e", "question": "What is the capital of Uzbekistan?", "answer": "Tashkent", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945f", "question": "How does Jack die in the movie \"The Shining\"?", "answer": "He freezes to death", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b4", "question": "What was studied by Project Blue Book?", "answer": "UFOs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febb9ae7e83c707845b213e", "question": "What kind of milk is used in chevre cheese?", "answer": "Goat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f025ff048f679a45aa97", "question": "Philematophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Kissing", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339430", "question": "What comedic duo of the 1920s and 1930s were real-life best friends?", "answer": "Laurel & Hardy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a919", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Dix?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b533", "question": "What is the point value of the letter K in Scrabble?", "answer": "Five", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133991f", "question": "What was the name of the first spin-off from the TV show \"Law & Order\"?", "answer": "Law & Order: SVU", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc50", "question": "Which University did Lady Gaga attend before dropping out to pursue her music career?", "answer": "New York University", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e32", "question": "In Greek mythology, whose death in the Aegean Sea, near Samos, was caused by melting wax?", "answer": "Icarus'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398af", "question": "Who won a Grammy Award for his song \"Mack the Knife\"?", "answer": "Bobby Darin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c7", "question": "How old was Sean Connery when he first appeared as James Bond?", "answer": "32", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc4dd6ce05a3942286f38", "question": "What is the name of the fishing boat that is featured in the film \"The Perfect Storm\"?", "answer": "Andrea Gail", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b85f", "question": "Which car company produced a model named the Celica?", "answer": "Toyota", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a05", "question": "What former athlete plays Matthew McConaughey\u2019s father in the movie \"Failure to Launch\"?", "answer": "Terry Bradshaw", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339400", "question": "Who was the name of Ray Liotta's character in the 1990 movie \"Goodfellas\"?", "answer": "Henry Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c4", "question": "The opera Aida was commissioned to mark what event?", "answer": "Opening of the Khedivial Opera House", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe52cd31bf59ab7d2e3810a", "question": "Why do crackers have holes in them?", "answer": "To prevent air bubbles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a1a4a012f2a7826b9b8732", "question": "In the movie \"Spaceballs\" what does the bumper sticker say on the back of Lonestar's ship?", "answer": "I love Uranus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7abbff048f679a45abee", "question": "Petrichor describes the scent of what?", "answer": "Outside after rainfall", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a17", "question": "Which composer of the \"Rite of Spring\" was still alive to see his music used in Disney's \"Fantasia\"?", "answer": "Igor Stravinsky", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5af25c21b63e5727cf5a485f", "question": "What year did the Foo Fighters release the song \"Learn to Fly\"?", "answer": "1999", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd1a", "question": "What bulb vegetable is traditionally worn on Saint David's Day?", "answer": "The leek", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b1", "question": "What describes the amount of light allowed to pass through a camera lens?", "answer": "Aperture", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be0e", "question": "Whose print of a banana is the cover of the 1967 album \"The Velvet Underground and Nico\"?", "answer": "Andy Warhol's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e3f5d35cb9e8bda682136b", "question": "Samuel Miller patented the first steam-powered what in 1806?", "answer": "Drill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b746", "question": "The serial killer Larry Eyler was also known as what?", "answer": "The Highway Killer/The Interstate Killer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a56c", "question": "Which US state is home to Cape Lookout National Seashore?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388de", "question": "Who competed against Athena to be the patron god of Athens?", "answer": "Poseidon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c327", "question": "What type of trees yield the resin used to produce turpentine?", "answer": "Pine Trees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f8", "question": "In the movie \"Pulp Fiction\", what is the name of the restaurant Mia brings Vincent to?", "answer": "Jack-Rabbit Slim's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c3", "question": "Which year was Marilyn Monroe born?", "answer": "1926", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a94c", "question": "The Republic of Upper Volta was the official name of which African country before August 1984?", "answer": "Burkina Faso", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7bb", "question": "In miles, approximately, how much Atlantic coastline does the state of New Hampshire have?", "answer": "18", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c356", "question": "What is odontophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Dentistry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cd40b2e685cf15b733e9888", "question": "What South American country's name comes from the Latin word for silver?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feddd3a6ce05a3942286da2", "question": "What alias does Andy use to launder the warden's ill-gotten money in the film \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Andy goes by the alias, Randall Stephens, to launder Norton's money.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe52db81bf59ab7d2e3810d", "question": "What is the best-selling ice-cream flavor in the US?", "answer": "Vanilla", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1fb", "question": "Who was the first Jewish Miss America?", "answer": "Bess Myerson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c375", "question": "What flaming dessert was created at Brennan's restaurant in New Orleans in the 1950s?", "answer": "Bananas Foster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a50e", "question": "Which river helped create the Grand Canyon?", "answer": "Colorado River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a068", "question": "What group was Ringo Starr with before the Beatles?", "answer": "Rory Storm and the Hurricanes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339024", "question": "What year did the first \"Where's Waldo?\" illustrated book hit the shelves?", "answer": "1987", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c5", "question": "In which Steven Spielberg movie does Audrey Hepburn star?", "answer": "Always", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a7", "question": "Who played Mad Max Rockatansky?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59524044736d4be723796b60", "question": "What island is the most populous in Canada?", "answer": "Island of Montreal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f77", "question": "What was Gladys Knight's backing band?", "answer": "The Pips", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c5c50775fa611bce67cb", "question": "Turmeric is a popular spice that is used in Asian dishes.  What other use does it have?", "answer": "Turmeric is also a powerful anti-inflammatory often used in traditional medicine.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b316", "question": "On April 11, 1990, California Angel Mike Witt combined with which starter to pitch a no-hit victory?", "answer": "Mark Langston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c96a", "question": "What sort of animal is a fennec?", "answer": "A fox", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6002447a4be4723ccac221a4", "question": "How long did it take Leonardo da Vinci to paint the Mona Lisa's smile?", "answer": "Leonardo's greatest triumph was the smile of the Mona Lisa, which he labored on for 16 years up until his death.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f16506df9b80650dbe7f93b", "question": "Where is ESPN's headquarters located?", "answer": "Bristol, Connecticut", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e5", "question": "Who directed the film \"Serpico\"?", "answer": "Sidney Lumet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339347", "question": "What does CSI stand for in the TV show by the same name?", "answer": "Crime Scene Investigation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde4cbfc6c6b019850c9a7e", "question": "What Indian Prime Minister guided India through its early years of independence after 1947?", "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bbc935f60f0007efaba0e5c", "question": "What is the name of Zorro's horse?", "answer": "Tornado", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b292", "question": "What piece of technology did IBM develop in 1973 that they nicknamed Winchester?", "answer": "A disk drive", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338987", "question": "What color was the hair of the girl known as Anne of Green Gables?", "answer": "Red", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339300", "question": "What song does Ferris Bueller sing from the float in the Chicago parade?", "answer": "Twist and Shout", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339209", "question": "What is the four-letter name of the groundhog in Groundhog Day?", "answer": "Phil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b1", "question": "What Shakespeare play asks: \"To be or not to be\"?", "answer": "Hamlet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5cd", "question": "What type of plane was the B-29 Superfortress?", "answer": "A bomber", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbea56ce05a3942286ef4", "question": "Which rock band performed at President Bill Clinton's first inauguration?", "answer": "Fleetwood Mac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523e3f736d4be723796b4d", "question": "Which region of Canada would you find Canada\u2019s Technology Triangle?", "answer": "Waterloo Region", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac4c", "question": "When was Queen Elizabeth II born?", "answer": "April 21, 1926", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c20", "question": "How did artist, Sting, earn his nickname?", "answer": "By wearing a black and yellow sweater", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a688", "question": "Lake Mohave lies several miles south of what larger lake?", "answer": "Lake Mead", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b010", "question": "Who did Abraham Lincoln replace as president?", "answer": "James Buchanan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c1", "question": "In The Simpsons, which character died by getting hit with T-shirts?", "answer": "Maude", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e804edde59ea584496fea7", "question": "Archie Moore was World Champion in what sport from 1952 to 1962?", "answer": "Boxing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015fcf6fe83fe1f2a824c48", "question": "What era marked the beginning of farming?", "answer": "Stone age", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ae8637d7f28483af1e7fdca", "question": "What country would you find Mount Elbrus in?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a971", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The House of Lords?", "answer": "The United Kingdom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133913f", "question": "Who composed the opera \"Death in Venice\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Britten", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58dba735874c93a3298b2162", "question": "A nail polish that is clear and goes on top of a colored polish is called what?", "answer": "Top coat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad4", "question": "In 2004, what golfer ended Tiger Woods' reign as the number 1 men's player in the world?", "answer": "Vijay Singh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049f03cf93664eb10486b7", "question": "What US state is home to the \"One Shell Square\" skyscraper?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600245024be4723ccac221ab", "question": "In Leonardo da Vinci's Annunciation, who is depicted with the virgin Mary?", "answer": "Gabriel -- The angel is sent by God to tell the virgin Mary that she will miraculously conceive and give birth to a son, Jesus.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339453", "question": "What does Henry join to avoid getting whacked in the 1990 movie \"Goodfellas\"?", "answer": "The Witness Protection Program", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db751e0ab2c8f322317fe4", "question": "Peridot is the birthstone for which month?", "answer": "August", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d98df08b8581f80b092b1", "question": "What day did Donald Trump assume office as the 45th President of the United States?", "answer": "January 20, 2017", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a121", "question": "For which movie did director John Schlesinger receive an Oscar in 1970?", "answer": "Midnight Cowboy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c33", "question": "Gilbert Stuart is best known for his work in what genre of painting?", "answer": "Portraits", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e4", "question": "What does the middle initial stand for in Arthur C. Clarke's name?", "answer": "Charles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c559", "question": "What color eggs do peacocks lay?", "answer": "They don't lay eggs - peacocks are male peafowl. Peahens are female and lay eggs.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a899b2560d398dc9cf7a69a", "question": "What type of animal is a Samoyed?", "answer": "Dog", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba28", "question": "Arthur Ashe is best known for his career in what sport?", "answer": "Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5f1b6ce05a3942286e3d", "question": "Elton John wrote the song \"Philadelphia Freedom\" as a tribute to what tennis star?", "answer": "Billie Jean King", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8eb", "question": "Graphite dust is formed when what is cut with a laser?", "answer": "Diamond", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e47", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"There's Something About Mary\"?", "answer": "Brett Favre", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd9a", "question": "What kind of lunch is the common British pub meal of a piece of Cheddar, crusty bread, and a pickle?", "answer": "Ploughman's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0ae1ee662d71a53650fb7", "question": "What two Renaissance artists were commissioned to paint rivalling frescoes at the Palazzo Vecchio in\u202fFlorence?", "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci and Michelangelo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaba", "question": "What is the capital of Solomon Islands?", "answer": "Honiara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008ddf6f4f3bc4a292f8626", "question": "In what city did American colonists dress as Native Americans and dump an entire, expensive tea into the sea", "answer": "Boston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea7e7fff048f679a45ac10", "question": "Belonephobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Pins and needles?", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76f37eec85e375820b2e4", "question": "Where was Mozart born?", "answer": "Salzburg, Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d0e62596a59cbdfbd383", "question": "Which country was the first to enact daylight savings time?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeeb", "question": "Which U.S. President ended his country's participation in the Vietnam War?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5cc", "question": "What is the name given to the largest number ever used in a mathematical proof?", "answer": "Graham's Number", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6aa9b20565ad31a57c81c", "question": "From which aircraft carrier did Lt. Col. James Doolittle's planes take off for the Doolittle Raid?", "answer": "USS Hornet", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea48caff048f679a45abb4", "question": "What snake has the longest fangs?", "answer": "Gaboon Viper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b328", "question": "What state did Harry Truman represent as a US Senator before becoming President of the Unites States?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a4b", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Chocolate War\"?", "answer": "Robert Cormier", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65dc71f3c0ead6880d621", "question": "What did God place at the east of the Garden of Eden after he drove out Adam and Eve?", "answer": "Cherubims", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a950", "question": "What is the only US state with only one syllable?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b242", "question": "What royal subject married Farah Diba?", "answer": "The shah of Iran", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cdcc1e347d002c297e4eb", "question": "President Richard Nixon called what songstress an \"Ambassador of Love\"?", "answer": "Pearl Baily", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cb2", "question": "Whose adventures on TV take place on the fictional Island of Sodor?", "answer": "Thomas the Tank Engine's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590680ddff9c0647b50a808f", "question": "What company was founded in October, 2016, to relaunch an all-electric vehicle that had previously failed?", "answer": "Fisker Inc.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2f0", "question": "Who played Ali in the 1984 film \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "Elisabeth Shue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a8", "question": "What song is most famous for its suggestive chorus of \"Voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)\"?", "answer": "Lady Marmalade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec2", "question": "Who created the Rubik's Cube?", "answer": "Erno Rubik", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0e", "question": "Moroni is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Comoros", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c054", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Iceland?", "answer": "Gyrfalcon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b8", "question": "What holds the bit in a drill?", "answer": "Chuck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59068223ff9c0647b50a809a", "question": "Which US Senator was nominated as Hillary Clinton\u2019s vice presidential running mate?", "answer": "Tim Kaine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe5250d1bf59ab7d2e380f1", "question": "Where did the word \"hamburger\" first appear in the US?", "answer": "In a Walla Walla newspaper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e93", "question": "Who made his West End debut playing alongside his mother in \"South Pacific\"?", "answer": "Larry Hagman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c497", "question": "Which French philosopher said \"Cogito Ergo Sum\"?", "answer": "Rene Descartes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339afe", "question": "What 1995 Kevin Costner film was the most expensive movie ever made, until \"Titanic\" came along in 1997?", "answer": "Waterworld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c422", "question": "What birds do Chinese and Japanese fisherman commonly use?", "answer": "Cormorants", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6b", "question": "Who played the role of TV's C. J. Barnes?", "answer": "David Spade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca7c", "question": "What is the significance of the moth found in the Harvard Mark I computer?", "answer": "First computer \"bug\"", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015eaccfe83fe1f2a824bf5", "question": "What does the color blue represent in the American flag?", "answer": "Blue symbolizes vigilance, perseverance and justice.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd7", "question": "Who wrote the book \"A Brief History of Time'' In 1988?\u00a0", "answer": "Stephen Hawking\u00a0", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59bb2911c9bff04efae6d754", "question": "In what 1967 film did Gene Hackman earn his first Oscar nomination?", "answer": "Bonnie and Clyde", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b534", "question": "What's the name of Barbie Doll's boyfriend?", "answer": "Ken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c48efbde8045e484669d", "question": "What is the name for a group of hyenas?", "answer": "A cackle or clan -- Hyenas are best known for the giggling, yipping sounds they make to express frustration and give warnings.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e94d0b65ea27d7a1303aed2", "question": "In a standard deck of cards, which of the face cards are the only ones whose hair is colored in a deck of playing cards?", "answer": "Jacks", "category": "general"}]